Chapter 3: The Art of Negotiation

The first thing Amelia Bones actually ordered done was have the Wizengamot chambers sealed.

It had taken her almost half an hour to issue that order, by which time several observers of the day's proceedings had stumbled out the doors. For all that the order was slow in coming, she wasn't shy about exercising her authority to contain the disaster. The two aurors present had been sent with all due haste to secure reinforcements, post guards at the doors, and retrieve the escaped observers by time turner shortly after their departure.

The remaining observers were in various states of shock, easily quarantined for the moment. That left the survivors of the Wizengamot itself, who were too busy pestering her to go stumbling through floo transports or manhandling owls to disseminate the day's events. The most important thing, at this point, was keeping everyone else out. Some news was simply too dangerous to escape into the wild.

Something would of course have to be done about the bodies eventually, but magic was efficacious in the short term and involved bringing no one else into the chambers.

Amelia idly wondered just how many memory charms might be necessary when all was said and done.

"Director Bones." Dumbledore startled her from behind. She turned. "Minerva and I really need to be getting back to Hogwart's soon. If there's anything we can do to help, please, let us know." He was leaning on Professor McGonagall for support.

"Albus, I could really use your input in this situation." Of all the times the old meddler could choose to not stick his nose in...

"He's an eleven-year-old boy, Amelia. And for all that he has acted improbably and harshly, I cannot believe he has gone to darkness yet. I might suggest talking to him."

"I don't even know what to say!"

"You have a niece about his age."

"My niece does not command dementors to kill people."

"Hmmm... I take your point. And yet, he is still only eleven. He only thinks he understands what it is to fight a war. Help him understand just what he has done this day." Suddenly then Dumbledore pulled close to her, pulled her ear to his mouth and whispered into it. "I fear the bigger difficulty will be finding a way out of this dilemma that does not alienate Harry completely. We need him, Amelia. We need him to defeat Voldemort."

He released her then, and she quickly schooled her face to show no shock. Dumbledore's eyes met hers, measuring her.

"I'll do what I can."

"And Amelia, there are children at Hogwarts affected by the tragic events here today, it would be far better were they to hear from us first. Do let me know what should be said, I have full faith in your discretion."

She nodded, dismissing him.

"Director Bones, I fear I must take my leave as well."

"Lord Malfoy, surely as someone injured in recent events you have some stake in the outcome."

"Then I might do the sensible thing and ask Master Potter what he wants, and give it to him."

"Lucius!" said a startled Madam Longbottom, "Unpleasant yes, but I never figured you for a coward!"

"When faced with an obviously superior opponent, discretion is frequently the better part of valor," Lucius snarled at her. "Good day Director Bones, Madam, Lords and Ladies."

"And what, might I ask, is so pressing that you would run out on this meeting?" Amelia asked.

"My son needs me," Lord Malfoy muttered. More strongly he continued, "And I imagine anything I propose would receive rather scant support in present company. Good day." With that he turned on his heel and headed for the door, pausing briefly here and there when he happened across the bodies of those who had been close allies.

The survivors of the 208th Wizengamot looked at each other solemnly. If Amelia were a betting woman, she'd wager Lucius was quite wrong in his prediction.

"Is Lord Malfoy right? Do we just roll over and give Potter what he wants?"

"Director Bones, how would the aurors fare if they simply tried to apprehend him?"

She tried to imagine it. Her aurors descending into the center of Azkaban, depending on their Patronuses to protect them from the dementors within. She could see it so clearly. The patronuses popping out of existence. The dementors swarming her brave aurors. You can't duel a dementor. She shuddered.

Every face was turned to her expectantly.

"I might note that both Lucius Malfoy and Albus Dumbledore have for once given us surprisingly similar advice," Amelia found herself saying. "Maybe we should talk to Master Potter and see if we can't find a way out of this."

She looked over the remaining members of the Wizengamot slowly, gauging their expressions. It wasn't a real solution, it was a fishing expedition. There would be discussion yet. But at least now there was something concrete to discuss.

She stared in wonder at her Patronus, her glowing human projection of emotion and will. Last week she would have been elated, indeed, there was an electric feeling of joy at her accomplishment. But everything was burdened with history and regret, making her mood more marked by a sardonic gravity than anything else.

"Hermione?" She realized he had been saying her name for about five minutes.

"Now what Harry?"

"Look, I don't know how much time we have, this is... um... sort of taking longer than I planned already, and they could have been here almost as fast as we were, so..."

"And?"

"Well, its not enough to decide dementors are evil and say that. A Patronus feeds off emotion, not reason... Um..."

"Spit it out Mr. Potter." Her voice was unnecessarily sharp, but her patience was rapidly waning, and she was cold and wet and just remembering that she could have cast a warming charm except now her wand was maintaining her Patronus.

"Hermione I'm sorry."

"I certainly hope so."

"I'm not talking about... look. About 100 yards that way," he motioned with his free right hand, "is one of the walls of Azkaban. At the end of that wall is a tower. And in that tower, more than half way up, is a woman."

Harry's voice had taken on a seriousness almost ridiculous in his unbroken high pitch. But Hermione wasn't dwelling on the tone, it was the message itself that was surreal and frightening.

"That woman has been sentenced to relive her crimes over and over again, all while under the influence of the dementors. And she sits in her cell repeating to herself No, I didn't mean it, please don't die! over and over again. And her voice is strong, she hasn't been here in Azkaban very long, the dementors haven't totally broken her spirit yet."

"Harry, why? What...?" she cried in panic and pain. Why was he telling her these things? It was horrible. She had only spent hours with a dementor, shielded by patronuses, and still she had felt sick. Inside her a flame, kindled when she had cast her patronus, ignited, burning with righteous indignation. Raw emotion poured down and out through her arm.

"She can't even remember the names of her children anymore," Harry continued, over her protests. "Maybe one year here, and her own children are lost to her."

Her Patronus grew then, and wonder mixed with horror as the light became brilliant, shifting from sapphire to white.

"And she's not even near the bottom. She's more than halfway up. There are cells all the way to the very bottom of the tower, right next to the dementors." Harry spit out the last sentence with venom.

She could see that his Patronus was undergoing a similar transformation to hers. He, too, was appalled by Azkaban. And as her Patronus waxed she could feel them, the prisoners of Azkaban, as the protective light spilled over them and shielded them.

Her dams broke and the silver light poured out from her as a river, wild and rapid, and she was almost emptied. But suddenly Fawkes was there, on her shoulder, cooing into her ear, and his warmth flooded into her and sustained her.

Harry Potter took her free hand in his then. He looked at her, and she could see the pain in his eyes. Though no more words were spoken, on this they were agreed.

Had anyone else been looking into the center of Azkaban just then, they would have seen one shining hominid patronus take the other's hand, standing together against the darkness of Azkaban.

Maybe Auror Li would have contacted Director Bones earlier if he understood the significance of his Patronus's bizarre fixed attention towards the center of Azkaban. But being stationed near dementors for long periods of time made the Patronus just another common everyday thing that got taken for granted. It protected you from dementors, that was what it did. It wasn't some sort of early warning system for unforeseen events. But so it was that Li's Patronus, and all the Patronuses of the other aurors in Azkaban, for that matter, had their attention fixed inward almost since Harry Potter had arrived. No one noticed.

However, when the window into the center suddenly lit up brighter than the noonday sun with silvery light, the aurors took notice. Li immediately contacted the DMLE home office, but by then it was too late.

When the light went out shortly thereafter, there wasn't a dementor left in Azkaban.

Whatever glowing light had suffused Azkaban was gone by the time Amelia Bones and entourage descended into its center, although the rain persisted as if nothing had changed. As the head of the DMLE and a member of the Wizengamot, she had volunteered to go as the body's sole representative, but certain others had insisted on coming as well.

Augusta Longbottom was not graceful on a broomstick, but she managed all the way down, ridiculous hat and all. Amelia had little idea why she had insisted on coming, but the old woman was cantankerous and unpredictable, and Amelia recalled she had a grandson in Harry Potter's class.

Theodorus Deas had also elected to accompany them, handling his broomstick with far more dexterity than Madam Longbottom. Mister Deas had been involved in the import and export of magical items and creatures, and little involved in politics, until near the end of the Wizarding War. When his wife was killed in the crossfire he had used his considerable economic influence to insert himself into the political life of Magical Britain, where he had been solidly against accomodation with Voldemort. He mostly drew his support from wizards engaged in businesses, and generally voted for measures that fostered peace and stability as he saw it. In the post-Wizarding War era, that generally meant siding with the likes of Dumbledore. If she couldn't fathom Augusta's presence, then Theodorus's insistence on accompanying them was as opaque as the worst riddle-twaddle from a Ravenclaw auror recruit. (And that was something she'd given up trying to figure out a decade ago).

They were flanked by four aurors. These aurors had patronuses out, because Amelia was not about to get eaten by dementors through negligence. They also had silence charms cast around their heads, and cotton stuffed in their ears in case the charms failed – its not like she was going to make it easy for Potter if this became ugly. That it was Azkaban made other precautions particularly tough to implement, because they couldn't apparate, portkey, or time turner within a mile in any direction. She wondered if that was intentional on Potter's part – not that he should have had any way of even knowing those things – but she was beginning to think that more than a healthy dose of paranoia was warranted at this point.

And if he did know those things, well, the location might be a defensive precaution on his part. Azkaban's future could not touch its past, which means nobody aware that Potter had come here could arrive before he did to ambush him. Given the events of the day thus far, Amelia was finding it surprisingly wise to assume that Potter, for all his youth, thought like Mad-Eye himself. The very idea was frightening.

The last of her precautions were a full twenty aurors on broomsticks well above Azkaban itself, and definitely outside of earshot, magically enhanced or not, of Potter. If necessary, they would do what had to be done.

The group landed without incident at the foot of the south wall, just below the auror station above. The patronus escort fanned out, covering Amelia and the two Wizengamot members from all sides as they proceeded northwards. Both Theodorus and Augusta were, like Amelia, keeping their hands well away from their wands, as instructed. This was to be a peaceful conversation if possible.

But you could tell something was wrong, almost immediately. Even with the patronuses, she should have felt something from the dementors. Where had Potter sent them?

Near the center she thought she saw figures ahead, vaguely outlined in the darkness and drizzle. Silently she signaled the more forward aurors to fall back a little, and strode calmly forward.

"Harry Potter? We just want to talk."

No answer.

She pushed forward through the gloom until the figures resolved themselves, and the stopped, confused. Harry was sitting crosslegged in the muck, the Granger girl passed out with her head on his lap. A phoenix – Fawkes? – perched on Granger's arm. Potter looked up at her when she stopped.

"Well hullo, I was wondering when you'd arrive."

She couldn't say anything, it was too incongruous. Augusta and Theodorus came up beside her on either side and similarly stopped.

"Adults have a strange way of wanting to talk."

"Ahem. Mister Potter," Madam Longbottom began, then stopped. She looked sideways at Amelia.

Amelia took a deep breath. "Mister Potter, as the duly appointed representatives of what's left of the Wizengamot, we've come to ask you what happens now."

"I surrender, of course."

Amelia blinked. Then she blinked again. "You... wait... what?"

"I surrender. There are conditions."

Amelia gave up. She wasn't paranoid enough for this.

It was Theodorus who managed to ask. "What conditions would those be, Mister Potter?"

"First, medical treatment for Miss Granger. Second, Miss Granger is released; no debts, no sentence, nothing. She goes back to Hogwarts or to some other suitable institution as she chooses. Third, well, I suppose we'll have to talk about the nature of my imprisonment, but that can probably wait for the time being."

The three representatives of the Wizengamot exchanged glances.

"Maybe we can continue this discussion somewhere other than in a freezing drizzle on an island of ooze that barely qualifies as land? Don't you want to take me into custody?"

Amelia shrugged her shoulders and was about to issue orders when Madam Longbottom blurted out, "But Mister Potter, what happened to the dementors?"

She didn't think she'd be able to erase the memory of his face, his eleven-year-old boy face, doing a fair impression of innocent youth, turning towards Madam Longbottom and saying sweetly "I ate them."

Amelia sputtered something unintelligible into her mirror instead of the command she intended.

"I'm sorry. I seem to have forgotten to snap my fingers."

Chapter 5: The Dust Settles

Harry stared at the old wizard in the wan light that splashed through the doorway from the outer room. He was suddenly very tired. Had been hoping, in fact, to be able to let go of his control at last and let the events of the last couple days become real to him. But then here was Dumbledore, purple hat slightly crumpled in his hands, keen intelligence shining from his eyes with reflected light, and no doubt looking for answers. Yet if Harry's perception hadn't failed him, the headmaster looked older. More worn down perhaps.

"What would you like to talk about, Headmaster?"

"I remember a boy, not much younger than you are now, who once told me that he wanted everyone to live forever. But now fifty-five people are dead. And there was a phrase this boy used, I notice that I am confused. Well, so it is, I notice that I am confused. What happened to that boy I knew?"

Harry stood there long moments, trying to compose a reasoned response, but all his carefully schooled control was gone, expended earlier. He had not the strength to summon it again. Instead he spoke, barely audible, "What would you have had me do?"

Dumbledore's eyes were hard. Measuring. But his voice was soft. "I confess, commanding a dementor to kill the people who disagree with you did not come to my mind as something that you might do at all, much less feel forced to do."

"They were going to murder her! As surely as if they'd cast the killing curse themselves!"

"For all that she is precious to us, Harry..." the old wizard reached out and put his hand on Harry's forearm. "For all that she is precious to us, she is just one girl."

"No." Harry shook off the hand, his voice going cold. "Do you have any idea how close you came to losing this war in those chambers?"

"Harry!"

"It's the Hermiones who make the fight worthwhile and necessary. Why do you think I'd defend a ministry who would simply slaughter them itself? If that's all that's left to lose, let Voldemort have it!" Harry was near tears, and he threw himself onto the bed, wanting nothing more than to be left alone.

Dumbledore stood, purple hat in his hands. He made no move to comfort. When he spoke, his voice low and sombre.

"I never said you should Harry. I formed the Order of the Phoenix, after all, because the government could not be trusted to fight the war itself. But there are plenty of good and decent people, other Hermiones, out there to fight for."

Harry made no response. He lay there and pressed his face into the pillow, but tears wouldn't come.

"What I fear is that you didn't spare a moment to think through the consequences to those other Hermiones. Have you endangered them more by your actions? When Voldemort comes openly, who will support you and who will oppose you? Before the lines might not have been drawn in black and white, but at least they had shape. Now the whole board is up-ended and the pieces in disarray."

Harry wiped at unshed tears, his eyes red, and forced himself to sit. "Its more than there being nameless good people out there. Hermione – she keeps me good, Headmaster. I need her. Her specifically. Without her... without her I don't know whose side I'd be on, when it came to it. I don't think I'd take Voldemort's side, but then there's more than two sides, isn't there?"

"Many more than two, and yet before they were known. While I might have disapproved of Lord Jugson, as deserving a man as might be found anywhere for the fate you determined, I knew who and what he was. I knew he was Lucius Malfoy's creature, and a Death Eater, and a blood purist. I could contemplate an action and project how he would react, what he might do. In but a few short years, his son will inherit his seat, barely more than a boy at the age of seventeen. His son I do not know. No, not nearly so well as I knew the father. Multiply that by fifty-five and the actions of the Wizengamot become suddenly mysterious."

"Now, the truth of what happened cannot be kept from the Wizengamot. The survivors were of course there. They saw. But the heirs of the dead – those that come after them – they will know the truth of what happened in their time. They will know to blame you, and they will feel the loss of their kin more keenly than the survivors feel the loss of their colleagues. What remains of the Wizengamot can be reasoned with today, but in just a few short years it will be your enemy, if you even have that long. You have made your road harder, that is for certain, but how hard? I cannot say. The full consequences can only be known in time, and time is a precious commodity. You have condemned us to flailing about in the dark while Voldemort draws ever nearer."

"As for Hermione herself, Harry, I don't know if she will ever come back to you. You may have saved her, but you may also have alienated yourself from her forever." Dumbledore met Harry's eyes at the end and held them.

"I know, Headmaster. Still, she was worth it, even if she won't speak to me again. I need her to remind me why I fight. What to fight for. That she lives is enough."

Harry paused for a moment before continuing. "As for the Wizengamot – I think you overestimate their importance Headmaster. They were impotent before, and likely will be again. Their actions will be beneath notice. And if they are more incompetent about their business than you expected, that can only be to my benefit."

"And you saw no other way to save Hermione than what you did? I would not make enemies needlessly, no matter how inconsequential you feel them to be."

"Headmaster, they had their wands virtually drawn and pointed at her head. I tried to find alternate solutions. I tried to talk them down, to get them to put their wands away. I failed. At the end of the day, wand, head. The only answer to force is force. And I couldn't defend myself upon that instant should they seek to turn their wands on me. My actions needed to be improbable. They needed to be drastic. They needed to be sudden. And they needed to disarm my opponent – the government of magical Britain itself – and make it incapable of resorting to violence again afterwards. Anything less would have failed, quite possibly spectacularly. Just one of the survivors casting a lethal or even incapacitating hex on me would have killed everyone with the dementor loose. That didn't happen only because I was sufficiently improbable, drastic, and sudden to make them hesitate."

"That doesn't mean fifty-five was the precisely right number, but there are limits to just how specific I could be." Harry's voice trailed off, but his thoughts raced on. The people who were kissed got kissed because they expected to be, and everyone else expected them to be. I couldn't say something like 'kiss all the death eaters', because I don't know where the weight of opinion of the chamber would have placed that expectation. But people who voted for sending Hermione to Azkaban were an immediately identifiable group in the aftermath of the vote. But he couldn't say that. Dumbledore wouldn't understand. He didn't have the frame of reference for the concepts involved. And besides, that knowledge was dangerous and exploitable. Far safer to leave it unvoiced.

His train of thought came to a safe place to resume, and he continued aloud. "And their votes had made them culpable in her attempted murder. It made them acceptable targets for retribution."

The headmaster sat beside him on the bed. When he spoke, he spoke facing away into the darkness of the room.

"I am concerned, Harry, that you are unwilling to let others even disagree with you. The Wizengamot thought, after all, that they were dealing with an attempted murderer."

"Should we treat with Voldemort then? Maybe we only have a disagreement." Harry's hands balled into fists.

"Harry!"

"When the Wizengamot does evil things and the good men and women who sit on it don't raise a finger to stop it, its no better than Voldemort himself."

The silence stretched, tense and uncertain. Harry found himself angry that he had to explain this. It should have been obvious.

"Have you no regrets?" Dumbledore finally asked, the kindness in his voice breaking the tension between them.

Harry, eyes wide and watery, held the headmaster's gaze. His anger abated. "I'm here, aren't I. I surrendered. Why would I be here if I didn't have regrets?"

"Harry, you are still an eleven-year-old boy. You can't bottle this up inside you."

"You were a hero once. Whose shoulder did you cry on?"

Albus Dumbledore had no response to that. They sat in silence for quite awhile.

Finally, Harry spoke, words said into the darkness and not to Dumbledore. "Maybe I'm not the hero they wanted. But I think I might be the hero they deserve."

Dumbledore stared at him sadly, but there was nothing more to say. And then there was only Harry and the darkness.

The door of the Headmaster's office flew open with a bang.

"Albus! I've been trying to see you for the last twenty-four hours! What in Merlin's name ha–" Snape sputtered to a stop. The sound of quill on parchment carried in the brief silence. "Minerva?"

"Good morning Severus." Minerva continued to write on the sheet in front of her.

"Where is Headmaster Dumbledore?"

"He's taken a leave of absence." She looked up. "You had news?"

"Voldemort is returned! Over half the Wizengamot dies under mysterious circumstances! And he chooses now to take a leave of absence!?"

"The headmaster was under a lot of strain. You had–"

"Do you have any idea how insane this is?!"

"Severus, I am really quite busy this morning."

He paused. "You're using his desk."

"I really couldn't be bothered to transfigure my own this morning. Now, either you have news that you wish to share, or you will let me get back to work."

"Yes, I have news." Snape composed himself. "Lucius sent no owls after... whatever... happened. No owls two nights ago. No owls last night. He had no visitors. He made no visits by floo or otherwise yesterday, except to the ministry. And aside from whatever ministry business he had during the day, he spent all his time in his study – alone or with Draco."

"And from this you conclude?"

"I don't know what to conclude. His political network was effectively destroyed in one day and he has done nothing."

McGonagall looked off for a moment before returning her attention to the potions professor. "Thank you Severus."

"This doesn't worry you at all?"

"I have to review the budget for the month, there's a meeting with the board of governors this evening that I must attend, disciplinary reports for several students from yesterday that I was unable to get to then which need reviewing, a detained defense professor that I will need to retrieve from the ministry, and sometime today I need to find time to grade thirty-five third year transmutation essays. And that's not even counting students who might need to see me today. I don't have time to be worried. Now, if that was all...?"

Severus stood there for a moment, pursing his lips. "The Headmaster's pet disaster, what role did he really play in all this?"

"Goodbye Severus."

Snape turned to go with a snarl of frustration.

"Oh, and Severus, while I'm acting Headmistress, I trust we will have the same arrangement you and Albus had?"

The potion master didn't answer as he strode from the room, the door closing behind him on its own.

Hermione hated keeping secrets. They gnawed at you, begging to escape into the open air. She especially hated secrets which forced her to lie to people. Which hadn't stopped her from acquiring several, although thankfully only one of them was one that anyone was likely to ask about. Of course, everyone wanted to ask, a fate she was saved from only because Professor McGonagall had, upon returning her to Ravenclaw Tower last night, been rather clear that anyone pestering Hermione about the last couple days would find themselves in an appointment with the Headmaster.

McGonagall hadn't actually said much to her last night. But she'd been abundantly clear that if anyone did ask, Hermione would tell them that the dementor had escaped and gone on a rampage. She would not mention Harry's involvement. She would absolutely not mention Azkaban. She would not under any circumstances explain the riddle of the dementors to her classmates. And if anyone asked about the phoenix on her shoulder, she would tell them that was between her and the Headmaster.

There were only two other things that McGonagall had said to her last night. She'd of course asked if Hermione was alright, because that's the kind of person Professor McGonagall was. And McGonagall had requested she go to the Headmaster's office after breakfast.

Inevitably this meant that breakfast was an uncomfortable affair surrounded by inquisitive Ravenclaws who desperately wanted to ask but sat silent because they didn't want to end up in the Headmaster's office. Hermione almost wished they would ask, it would have been better than the uncomfortable silence. Maybe. She'd still have to lie.

And those were only her peers who were willing to sit close enough to her that they could have asked. Reactions to her arrest by aurors were apparently complicated, not that anyone was actually talking to her – as much as some of them apparently wanted to be – to even broach the subject. But in addition to the silence of unasked questions around her there were the dirty stares from farther down the table. And from the other tables, excepting only Gryffindor. They'd given her a standing ovation when she walked into breakfast, and she really wasn't sure how she should feel about that.

Hermione glanced up at the head table. McGonagall was absent, which wasn't terribly surprising given Dumbledore's parting words. Snape was also, thankfully, absent, as was Quirrel. Flitwick's attention was sternly on his house's table, although he did spare a smile for her when he noticed her looking. Sprout had a concerned expression on her face, her eyes flitting around the hall, frowning as she looked from table to table. And Trelawney was oblivious, as usual.

She was glad that Fawkes had been willing to stay in her room, at least she thought he'd stay in her room. If anything, the silence and the stares would have been that much weirder with a phoenix on her shoulder.

Her eyes wandered to the Slytherin table. Draco was not there. Hadn't been there when she came to breakfast. Draco, who was always there just when food arrived. Maybe he hadn't gotten back yet? She looked away; the half of Slytherin that wasn't staring daggers at her was studiously pretending she didn't exist. He was alright, wasn't he? She wasn't sure she'd be okay if he wasn't alright, even if she did choose to believe Harry that she hadn't done anything. No, that way lay madness. She had to believe Harry that she hadn't actually done it.

Hermione caught herself pushing food around her plate instead of eating. She put her fork down. No reason to delay this any longer. She felt eyes track her as she stood up from the table, turned, and walked towards the door.

Just before she reached the sanctuary of the doorway, however, there was Draco. Uncharacteristically late for breakfast, but there all the same. Her eyes went wide and she inhaled sharply. She thought she saw Draco flinch away from her, afraid, but then he schooled his expression, turning his nose up at her.

"Miss Granger," he sneered. Dismissive. Crabbe and Goyle glared at her over Draco's shoulders.

Hermione couldn't answer, not there in front of the other students. She closed her eyes and turned her head away, towards the wall. She felt the air shift as they walked past her.

"I'm sorry," she whispered into the wall, but there was no one still near enough to hear.

Hermione found herself before the solid oak door to the headmaster's office. The gargoyle had been waiting for her and stepped aside without any prompting. The spiral stairs hadn't taken nearly long enough. So here she was, standing on the threshold with some trepidation, and sorely tempted to go back down without entering. Maybe just tempted. Its not like Dumbledore was going to be there. It would probably be Professor McGonagall, which meant no crazy old wizard playing mind games with her, even if the crazy was only for pretend.

She realized this was the first time she'd come to this office by herself.

Hermione raised her hand to knock, but before she could lay knuckles to wood it swung open, leaving her caught with her hand raised and her mouth open in surprise.

"Do come in Miss Granger."

"How did..."

"Magic." McGonagall smiled.

"But that doesn't... That's not an answer!"

"I am glad to see you're feeling better."

Hermione supposed flustered was better than feeling guilty and weird and stared at. A chair was positioned before the desk, so she sat in it.

"So is there anything you want to talk about, Miss Granger?"

"I... you..." Wait, hadn't McGonagall insisted she come?

"Miss Granger, I understand it was a rough weekend, but you are only twelve. I thought you might want to talk about what happened."

Hermione chewed her lip, trying to put words to something. Anything. She must have been frowning because Professor – no, Headmistress – McGonagall was looking at her with slightly more concern. "I'm not sure how I'm supposed to feel about everything. I mean, there's the awful memories of me actually doing that to Draco, and whether they're real or fabrications like Harry insists, I still have them. And then there's the awful... of listening to Harry... his willing to do just about anything... give away his fortune... risk his life... and listening to that with a dementor right behind me. And then there's the horror of the dementor loose and killing people. And..."

"Miss Granger – Hermione – a twelve-year-old girl shouldn't have to live with such things. I can take those memories from you, if only for a time."

"No!" Her vehemence surprised her. "I mean, there was awful and horror, but there was also a shining moment of light in Azkaban, and I don't think the one makes sense without the other. And how can I make up for what I did or think I did if I can't remember?"

"But you didn't do anything."

"I did! I went to breakfast as if nothing had happened, and I knew! Good girls shouldn't do that! Heroes shouldn't do that."

"Hermione, in my experience, no one is that good."

"Well they should be! And how can I apologize to Draco if I can't remember what I did wrong?"

"... Apologize?"

"I suspected him of plotting against me and he wasn't. He was helping me, or thought he was, in his own mysterious Slytherin way. I heard his testimony read out just like you did." Hermione paused for a moment. McGonagall had also witnessed the dementor's attack. "Headmistress... how are you doing... after..."

Was the usually unflappable Headmistress taken aback?

"I... no one has thought to ask me that. Thank you. I'm... well, mostly I'm disappointed in Mister Potter."

"Oh." She was chewing on her lip again and made herself stop. "Is Dumbledore ever coming back?"

"I don't think I can give you a good answer to that."

"He seemed so sad when we spoke yesterday. Worn out."

"I didn't realize he had been in to see you."

"Headmistress McGonagall, what's going to happen to Harry?"

"Mister Potter will not be coming back to Hogwarts, I'm afraid. He's agreed to be incarcerated, admittedly under rather generous circumstances, for awhile. I could arrange for you to visit if you'd like."

"No. No, I don't think I want that..."

"Do you want to talk about it?"

Her feelings about Harry were... complicated. Yes, that was definitely the right word. How could she even begin to make sense of them?

"He's just so terrifying, and meddling, and unpredictable, and I can't believe he did that for me..." She couldn't believe she was actually vocalizing this, but she couldn't stop now. It just exploded out of her mouth. "I mean... the things he offered for my freedom... I don't know how to feel about that. How he was willing to give away all his money and possibly sacrifice his life for me. How is a person supposed to feel about that? And then he killed people. For me. Can you do that and still be good? Because there was so much light inside him in Azkaban. But he didn't ask. He never asks. And–"

"Hermione."

"And there was a thing he said, awhile ago, about how he could try to keep me safe and protected, but he knew how that part of his life would go and he was skipping it, and I honestly have no idea what part of his life that would have been, but I'm finding that sentiment deeply worrying..."

"Miss Granger."

"I mean – he's not my boyfriend!"

"Miss Granger!"

Hermione managed to stop her mouth from working, although her brain hadn't managed the same. It kept running at sixty kilometers a second inside her head. Wait. Did McGonagall look... uncomfortable. The sight of the frown on McGonagall's face while she searched for something to say finally brought Hermione's brain to a halt in a train wreck of unvoiced sentiment.

"Boys... boys are complicated." The Headmistress sighed. "No, not just boys, people are complicated. But it's alright if you have feelings for him and think he did wrong."

"But its not about feelings. Well, not about those kinds of feelings." Hermione managed a frown. "I'm not convinced he was wrong."

"Hermione! He killed fifty-five people! He blackmailed the entire government!" She paused briefly before continuing, almost under her breath. "And I fear he broke the Headmaster."

"He's the only person who went in there with me as his highest priority. The only person. No one else was willing to be responsible for me!"

"I'm not sure responsible is–"

"Everyone had some other agenda, even Dumbledore. Only Harry was willing to do whatever it took to save me. Which is extremely worrying and I really don't know how to feel about that. But I'm here and not being eaten by dementors, now, solely because of Harry."

"I'm really not sure considering Mister Potter responsible is a good idea..."

"No, of course not. Harry... I'm not sure he's good enough for the kind of responsibility he sees himself as having."

"I'm glad we agree."

"Which is why I need to hurry up and learn as much as I can because someone has to be responsible for saving magical Britain from Harry." That really wasn't what she'd been intending to say.

"Miss Granger!"

"I don't think anyone else can do it," she finished. "Harry won't listen to anyone else. Not really. Not like he'd listen to me. Its the only way I can keep everyone else safe."

"No one person should have to feel responsible for so much. Miss Granger, you're only twelve!"

Later, Hermione wouldn't be able to say why she said it. She could see how shocked McGonagall was afterwards. Had grimaced as she stood up and mumbled an apology before she fled the room. But she'd said it all the same, the last words Godric Gryffindor had penned in his biography, in roughly accented latin.

"Non est salvatori salvator, neque defensori dominus, nec pater nec mater, nihil supernum."

After that, well, there really wasn't anything left to add to the conversation. And as it was she was going to be late to Herbology.

"Daphne, you should come down for lunch."

"Go away Tracey."

Daphne lay sprawled on her bed, her face buried in a pillow.

"You already missed class this morning. And breakfast."

"I don't care!" A sob escaped the girl, and she started crying again.

"Daphne, you have to come down sometime. Maybe you want to talk about it?"

Tracey dodged the flying pillow which suddenly launched itself from the bed at the end of Daphne's arm. The scion of the most ancient and noble house of Greengrass sat glaring at her, eyes red, tears running down her face, and hair in disarray.

"My mother is dead. Go away and leave me be." And with that Daphne turned and buried her head in another pillow, muffled sobs escaping into the room.

This just wouldn't do at all. Her friend was hurting. There had to be something Tracey could do to fix this. Or at least make it better.

"Might as well leave her to mope," Pansy Parkinson said as Tracey walked back into the common room. "She clearly doesn't care."

What kind of Slytherin would she be if she couldn't come up with something, some clever plot to help fix this. A smile broke across her face, a sharp unfriendly smile she directed at Pansy. She'd had an idea. Oh yes, she'd show them. She'd show them all.

A/Ns: First, Professor Quirrel's captivity, questioning, and release happens exactly as it does in HPMoR. Nothing in this fic will have altered that.

Second, time to address some comments. Keep in mind that HPMoR (up to chapter 82 and including the Quirrel scenes thereafter) is canon.

Simply speaking the truth about patronuses wouldn't cause them to pop. They'd have to believe him.
-No, simply speaking is actually quite sufficient. This is canon in HPMoR. Its explicitly laid out in chapter 82 (iirc) of HPMoR and implied in the last Humanism chapter. Remember, the patronus charm works by thinking about happy thoughts *instead of* death. One of the reasons he doesn't tell Dumbledore is because it would ruin Dumbledore's ability to use his patronus even if he doesn't believe Harry. Belief is not necessary.
-Lets imagine a hypothetical charm that works by thinking about happy instead of elephants. While you're doing this, I tell you not to think of an elephant. You don't have to believe me that there is or isn't an elephant, but you're definitely thinking about them. Which explicitly causes the charm to fail. Just mentioning elephants in a context related to the charm is sufficient. Same deal, except replace elephants with death.

Harry is a transhumanist, wouldn't kill people
-This is the premise of the fic, that Harry goes with his plan of last resort from the trial, the one he explicitly thinks about in HPMoR. Think of the fic as a "What if Harry was forced to go with this other idea he had." Implausibility is no barrier to a what if? scenario. Not that it could be all that implausible if he actually and seriously thought about doing it. (Which he did...).
-Also remember that Harry is ultimately a consequentialist. (Which is why I personally hate Chapter 85, because its about as anti-rationalist as you can get - do note that in 85 he's not trying to justify limited killing, he's trying to justify not killing at all instead of limited killing). That means that whatever actions result in the best consequences are the ones he should take.
-Now, the biggest problem with consequentialism is, while it is a basis for moral reasoning between two options given known preferences in outcomes, it doesn't provide a way to adjudicate which outcome is better in itself. So while Harry is going to be weighing the ultimate consequences to the best of his ability to predict, which consequences he cares more about will be more or less rational based on how rational his heirarchy of values is. And as is established canon in HPMoR, Hermione causes him to behave in ways that appear irrational to others. In short, she's really high up in his heirarchy of values whether you think she should be or not. To bring the point home, consider someone who actively prefers nuclear war breaking out to its absence. He'll be prefering rather different consequences than most people. While extreme, it does highlight the limitations of consequentialism.
-Now, Harry has elucidated some other consequences he thinks will be better or at least no worse following his actions in my fic as well. Just like his 'owl hand grenades to Death Eaters' off-the-cuff proposal, there is a brutal elegance to this solution. There are also obvious problems. I think Harry has a reasonable case to be made, especially since he was seriously outgunned and working on an excessively limited time frame. Which isn't to say he's right, but he isn't obviously wrong either.

Actually, that's the most important thing you should get out of that rather lengthy answer: Harry isn't necessarily right. No attempt has been made, not by EY and certainly not by myself, to hammer out an objective scheme of morality. And while HPMoR is an author tract in which Harry often speaks with EY's voice, that is not the case here. Harry is fallible, even if reasonably rational and of genius level intelligence. But he isn't going to be obviously wrong either. If you think he was obviously in error, check your moral assumptions and see where Harry might disagree with you. (And if you think you can elucidate an objective system of morality, please, do so and get your PhD in philosophy already). What he should be is consistent, and his willingness to go to frankly insane lengths for Hermione and his tendency to escalate until he wins should not be ignored when considering exactly how far he'd go. (As HPMoR chapter 85 does not happen in my fic, it is not canon here and Harry has not had those thoughts).

Long author note is long. Feel free to disagree with me, but don't expect me to change the story concept just because you do.

Chapter 7: Awkward Overtures

"Can we back up a bit?" Susan Bones had an expression on her face that should have been familiar to Hermione. It said, to use few words, why are my classmates totally insane?, although the implied question mark made by the arch of her eyebrows was likely rhetorical.

"But what if she's not Neville's soulmate!" Hannah interjected. Hermione exchanged a resigned glance with Susan over the other Hufflepuff's head.

"Well, they figure that out, I guess. Later." Tracey pondered for a moment, which was a long time for Tracey. "And maybe they are soulmates. But I don't think they have to be soulmates for Neville to help distract Daphne."

"I thought being soulmates was one of those things you just knew."

"Have you actually had a soulmate?"

"Well, no."

"So how do you know what you know?" Wait, had Tracey just asked a Harry question?

"Everyone says so!"

"I don't think any of them have had a soulmate either!"

"Well... um... maybe we should ask someone who has one?" Two faces swiveled expectantly towards Hermione. "General Sunshine... um... when did you realize Harry was your soulmate?"

Hermione fidgeted. Susan smirked in schadenfreude.

"He's not. Hannah, there's no such thing."

"Well that just makes me feel worse."

"But..."

"If there aren't any soulmates, then maybe Neville and Daphne end up together even if it isn't meant to be. And if its not meant to be, that means someone else could have ended up with Neville, if she were perhaps a little braver or..."

"Look, even if Neville gets Daphne to leave her room, there's nothing to say they'll even go on a date much less..."

"They're going to get married!" Hannah grabbed Hermione's arm and started sobbing into her shoulder.

"Err..." Hermione beseeched Susan with her eyes.

"Fix this." Susan had a serious expression.

"Um... Hannah, no one is saying that you... that she... doesn't have a chance with Neville. No one was going to give us a chance to be heroes, remember, so we made our own chances."

"You think that could work?" Hannah looked up hopefully from Hermione's arm.

"Well, in retrospect, trying to be heroes didn't go exactly the way I'd intended..."

"But we were heroes."

"Um... I'd like to think so."

"Okay. I know what I have to do."

"Don't... ah... don't do anything I wouldn't do?"

Hannah was already on her feet and moving towards the door to the Hufflepuff common room. There was a moment of confusion as the other three girls looked at each other.

"Oh this is probably going to be too good to miss," Tracey said. She hopped to her feet.

"What have I done..."

"I don't know, but you're going to watch." Susan Bones offered her hand to Hermione, who was the last one still sitting.

They hurried after Hannah.

Neville was sitting on a couch in the Hufflepuff common room, working on Transfiguration homework. Hannah walked straight from the door toward where Neville was sitting, but he didn't notice her until she was standing over him.

"Hannah?" Neville said, looking up. "Have you been crying?" He put his homework to the side and patted the empty spot next to himself on the couch.

Hannah had other ideas. She sat down across his lap, her feet dangling off one side, her arm near him wrapped over his shoulder and around his back for balance. Neville's arm came up to her back by automatic reflex to steady her.

"Um, Hannah?" Neville managed to get out before Hannah grabbed his tie with her other hand, closed her eyes, and pulled his lips into hers. There was a moment of silence in the common room, all eyes on the two first years. Then the applause started.

From the doorway the three other former SPHEW members looked on dumbfounded.

"I didn't think she had it in her," Tracey said to no one in particular from the doorway.

"Sweet Merlin, I caused this," said Hermione next to her.

"It is something you did," Susan remarked dryly.

"Harry was demented at the time!"

Neville had never actually managed to close his eyes. As Hannah released his tie and sat back, looking inordinately pleased with herself, he still hadn't managed to react. Unless you count the bright red blush which brought out his freckles, a blush that Hannah was mirroring. She brought her free hand up and ran a finger over the freckles on his cheek with a giggle.

"Ms. Abbott," the voice of Professor Sprout cut across the common room. "My office, now." Sprout cast a disapproving sidelong glance at the three students in the doorway before turning in the direction of the Hufflepuff Head-of-House office.

Hannah was glowing as she got to her feet. She almost bounced in the direction Professor Sprout had disappeared in. The eyes of every young girl in the room followed her, only one pair of which looked on guiltily. Only after Hannah disappeared from view did the animated chatter of gossip start.

On the couch, Neville finally found his senses and his voice. His confused "What?" was almost inaudible against the excited murmurs of near a hundred teenage girls.

"So do you think we can still use Neville to cheer up Daphne?"

"I'm not so sure... oh, I don't know anymore. Just promise me no stunning?"

"You're taking all the fun out of this, 'Mione."

It was getting close to curfew when Hermione finally returned to Ravenclaw Tower. She hadn't even started the twenty inches due in astronomy tomorrow, which wasn't like her at all. Hopefully, whatever she managed before breakfast tomorrow morning wouldn't terribly offend Professor Sinistra.

The common room had mostly cleared out, which made it less uncomfortable, but she still headed directly to the sleeping room she shared with the other first-year Ravenclaw girls. The only occupant of the room was Padma Patil, brushing her hair out before bed. Well, her and Fawkes, who left his perch on her bed and flew over to her as she came in.

"Hi Fawkes, sorry I left you here all day. I could've maybe used you earlier, to remind me just how suspect my judgement can be." Fawkes nuzzled her as she stroked his back, an admittedly strange sensation as the flames licked her fingers but did not burn.

"You know Hermione, we don't all hate you," Padma said from her bed. "You don't need to stay away from Ravenclaw until everyone is getting ready for bed." Her brush continued in even strokes.

"It wasn't just that, I was... Tracey wanted... oh Merlin, I think we broke Neville."

"Neville Longbottom?"

"You didn't hear? Hannah kissed him in front of all of Hufflepuff. I figured it would be all over the school by now..." Hermione walked over to a bedpost and set Fawkes on it.

"Well, the rumor mill seems to go through Slytherin, not exactly a Hufflepuff friendly house. Wait, what does that have to do with you and Tracey?"

"Well, I might have caused Hannah to... what's this?" There was a letter on her pillow.

"I dunno, it was there when I came in."

Hermione sat down with a concerned look on her face and carefully opened the letter.

To Hermione, the first Granger

Miss Granger,

It would seem we need to talk. Mr. Potter is important to both of us, and some accomodation must be reached between our houses to put our animosity behind us. However, it would be folly to be seen meeting in public. I have enclosed directions to a location at which our secrecy may be assured, and might suggest tomorrow night at the stroke of eight as a suitable time when our absences may not be marked as unusual. You may signal your agreement by being present at breakfast when the food appears. I strongly recommend destroying this letter after reading it.

It was signed with an ornate script M.

"Hermione, you've gone white. What is it?"

Hermione quickly read the directions to the meeting place before carefully folding the letter.

"Hermione?"

"It's nothing." Her wand was suddenly in her hand. She held the letter away from her by a corner, as if it might bite her. "Incendio!" The letter burst into flames, burning down towards the held corner quickly. She held on until the last second, when it started to burn her fingers, before dropping it and stamping out the flames with her foot.

"That didn't look like nothing."

"I can't talk about it."

"Hermione, don't put all your friends at arm's length, okay? You're starting to act like Harry, and not in a good way."

"It's... I can't talk about it."

Padma put her brush down and gave Hermione a penetrating look. "Well, when you can talk about it, remember you have friends?"

"I know, and I'm sorry." Hermione threw herself down on her bed, still fully dressed. She hadn't actually been planning on going to sleep yet, just think through the events of the day and try to make sense of it all. But Fawkes had sensed her distress and floated down to perch on her upper shoulder. The song of the phoenix was warmth and comfort, and before she knew it she had drifted off.

Hermione was present when the food appeared the next morning. Actually, she was present half an hour before the food showed up. The mostly deserted dining hall made as reasonable a place to continue her hastily written astronomy homework as anywhere else, and she hadn't wanted to be late. She'd sat at the far end of the Ravenclaw table, to reduce the number of potential neighbors, because she really wasn't feeling social this morning. The letter had twisted her stomach in a knot. Breakfast itself might not be on the agenda, which wasn't a total loss; it meant she'd have more time to try to finish her homework.

The food hadn't yet appeared when Tracey sat down next to her, all energetic enthusiasm as she bumped Hermione's shoulder getting her legs over the bench.

"Hey 'Mione, working on anything important?"

Hermione didn't look up from what she was writing, although her concentration was spoiled. "Just trying to finish the astronomy homework. Someone's crazy scheming kept me distracted last night."

"You aren't going to tell me that wasn't worth it..."

"I don't try to make a habit of breaking people, especially friends."

"Hannah was going to morosely crush on Neville forever, and never act on it, without outside intervention. And she didn't look so broken on the way to Sprout's office." Tracey smiled foolishly. "And be honest, that was a pretty amazing kiss. I wish Harry was here. I might try that on him."

"Oh please, I already know what he'd say..."

Tracey made glasses with her fingers. "I'm sorry Tracey, but I've already fallen for Hermione."

"No. He'd say 'I told you no kissing.'"

"You're just worried I could steal him away."

Hermione finally looked up, frowning slightly. Tracey had this huge open-mouthed smile.

"I'm just teasing, 'Mione. But a girl can dream, right?"

Hermione gave a hesitant smile and blushed lightly. "I suppose it was a nice kiss. Even if Neville had no idea what was going on."

"I wonder if she practiced..."

"Practiced? With whom?"

"You know, other girls. Haven't you ever practiced kissing with your friends, so you wouldn't be a bad kisser when a boy kissed you?"

"Uh... no?"

"Maybe Harry doesn't want to kiss you because you aren't a very good kisser then."

"What? But... how could someone even know such a thing? Also, I don't think Harry has much basis for comparison..." Hermione shifted uncomfortably. This was going to be another one of those conversations.

"It's entirely possible boys kiss each other to practice, too. Maybe you could try asking him?"

"About kissing other boys?" That sounded like a conversation doomed to be embarrassing for anyone involved in it.

"No no no, about whether he thinks you're a good kisser or not. But I suppose a boy might lie about it, to spare your feelings, if he liked you. And you're like the only girl Harry really notices, so he must like you."

"I... um... I don't know."

"Oh come now, everyone else sees it. Even I see it, as much as I wish he'd notice me more."

"Well, its not like he's come out and said 'Hermione, I really like you' or anything." It was possible, she was willing to admit, at least to herself, that she'd like to hear him say that. Or at least had until recently entertained such notions. Before this past weekend recently. This was probably connected to the reason her cheeks were starting to feel warm. "And, I mean, it's not like he's my boyfriend."

"Don't be silly, boys don't say stuff like that. Not without prompting. And if he's not your boyfriend then at least one of you is in denial."

"Why can't a girl and a boy just be friends and be sensible about the whole thing?" Not that there was anything sensible about a boy who killed over fifty people for you, but she couldn't even mention that part to Tracey. Besides, it would probably only strengthen the Slytherin's convictions about Harry and her romantic entanglement. It wasn't clear Tracey would understand why that wasn't romantic.

"'Boys are only thinking about one thing' my mum told me, although she won't tell me what it is, but I'm pretty sure it has to do with kissing; she looks at my father and smiles when she says it, even though her tone says she's warning me about something. My mum is a little weird."

Hermione arched one eyebrow at the babbling Slytherin.

The food chose this moment to appear, which gave Hermione a chance to notice that the room had started to fill up several minutes prior, and now the multitude of conversations had blended into an indecipherable background hum. She managed to notice Draco had arrived with his usual promptness and was already sitting down to breakfast. Of course he didn't look in her direction, that she noticed anyway, but he was much better at whatever cloak-and-dagger game she had found herself playing than she was. Hermione really didn't want to let her gaze linger on the Slytherin table longer than she had to, but she did spare a few moments to confirm that Daphne had not come to breakfast, at least not yet.

A startled gasp and Tracey's hand gripping her upper arm alerted her to something going on in front of her, so she turned to follow Tracey's gaze to the Hufflepuff table. Hannah had wrapped her arms around a rather startled Neville from behind, and was currently saying something into his ear that was making him blush furiously.

"It's really too bad we can't hear what they're saying," Tracey commented as Neville said something that made Hannah frown. The normally shy Hufflepuff stormed off and sat at the other end of the table dramatically. A gaggle of first through fourth year Hufflepuff girls clustered around her.

"I should probably talk to her..."

"Well, I need to talk to Neville about Daphne. Wish me luck." The chaos legion theme song chose that moment to start playing in her head, an ominous chorus of 'Doom doom doom doom-doom-doom doom-doom-doom', but that might have just been Tracey humming it as she walked away.

Most of her own house was still avoiding her, which meant Tracey had been the only person sitting near her at the end of the long table. Hermione absent-mindedly spooned something edible into her mouth without noticing what it was as she turned her attention back to her astronomy homework. Hannah would have to wait, she had six inches left to write and she was running out of time. So engaged, she was totally surprised when Padma sat down next to her.

"What was Tracey sitting here for?" the Indian witch asked. "I mean, she's not making any friends in her own house hanging out with you, right?"

"I'm no good at those kind of games, so how should I know? Maybe there's a faction who hate Draco and are secretly applauding me."

"Really?"

"No, I just made that up. I have no idea why Tracey is willing to sit with me in public."

"Well, what was she talking to you about?"

"Um..." Hermione colored. "... boys," she finally managed, speaking softly.

"Ooh, who does Tracey like?"

"That's a... complicated... subject." No, that didn't even begin to describe it. Hermione forced herself to stop thinking about her conversation with Tracey yesterday. That way lay madness and enough embarrassment to make her want to hide in her room.

Tracey chose that moment to return, sitting down across from the two Ravenclaws since the spot next to Hermione was now taken.

"Neville says he'll do it, but he wants to talk to you first Hermione."

"Wait, Neville will do what?" Padma asked. She looked back and forth between the two of them. "I thought Hannah and... and obviously Hermione and... what is Hermione going to do with Neville?"

"Hermione and Neville?" Tracey snickered. "I wouldn't dare insult my lord Potter in such a way. No, Neville is going to help us get Daphne to rejoin the land of the living and homework suffering masses!" She finished with the back of her hand dramatically pressed against her forehead in a mock swoon.

"Don't remind me, I still have to write five more inches for astronomy!"

"You're not done with your homework yet?" Padma looked at her like she had turned into a cat. "Are you feeling alright, Hermione?"

"Ask me at the end of the week..."

"There's no time for homework, Hermione. We need to get Neville to Daphne right after breakfast!"

"But... I have class..."

"And so do the Slytherins! You thought I was going to walk you and Neville through the Slytherin common room while there were Slytherins still in it? And they call me crazy..."

"Oh..."

"Doesn't Neville also have class?" Padma asked.

"Well, yeah, but he's kinda freaked out by Hannah, apparently, and since classes are scheduled by house... he seemed more than willing to ditch at least one."

Hermione was writing frantically while Tracey and Padma gossiped, cringing at the mess her hurried handwriting became. It was probably the worst essay she'd ever written, but done was better than not done. Finished at last, she turned to Padma.

"Could you turn this in for me?"

"Sure Hermione. Just don't go bad girl on us and start skipping all your classes." Padma smiled mischeviously as she said it.

Hermione thought of how Daphne must be feeling. "Some things are more important than class."

Tracey stood up and leaned over the table. "I'll go tell Neville to meet us in the hallway outside in a few minutes," she whispered in Hermione's ear. "We shouldn't be seen leaving together, after all."

Hermione nodded mutely as she put away her pen and paper. With a quick look around the dining hall, she let out a sigh and walked out with her breakfast mostly untouched.

It wasn't long before Tracey turned the corner. She made a conspiratorial smile, but otherwise remained blissfully silent. A few minutes later Neville joined them.

"Hi Hermione. Look, I'm not sure this is a great idea, and I'm not sure what I can say, but Tracey did point out that I knew what it was like to lose a parent, so maybe I can help and maybe I can't. I'm willing to try. But I need you to promise me something."

Hermione cast an impressed glance at Tracey. "Well, I don't honestly know what I can promise, but I want to make this work. For Daphne. Because I know what she's going through is awful."

"Just promise me you don't expect me to kiss her."

A/N: I had originally hoped to have this posted by Feb 14th, for obvious reasons. This failed. I was knocked-out sick for 4 days leading up to that week, and one character did something I totally didn't expect which derailed me. I'm sure you can guess who that was. I'm still not totally happy with it, and my beta has expressed some larger story concerns that I can't really disagree with, but February is almost over, so here it is. There may be some alterations in the future, either with next month's update or as I start working on the next arc.

The plan is still to finish this arc next month. Unless of course I don't, in which case it will definitely be over with April's update. There's several things that need to happen, but I'm optimistic it will all happen in March.

The next arc will involve some Harry, and also more thinking big about what's going on in Magical Britain. (This of course makes me increasingly anxious about what EY's actual plans are... Bridge to be burned with radioactive fire when I get there.)